number10.gov.uk 2013-04-19

# Privacy Policy - Number 10

This statement covers the services provided by the Number 10 website.

The Data Controller for this website is the Cabinet Office Openness Team.

The purpose of this statement is to inform users of the Number 10 website, which is managed by the Prime Minister’s Office, about what information is collected about them when they visit this site, how this information is used, if it is disclosed and the ways in which we protect users’ privacy.

### Confidentiality and security

Any information you provide will be held securely and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. Your personal details will not normally be disclosed to third parties. In some circumstances however we may need to disclose your personal details to a third party so that they can provide a service you have requested, or fulfil a request for information. Any information about you that we pass to a third party will be held securely by that party, in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998, and used only to provide the services or information you have requested.

You have a right to access the personal information we hold about you at any time. If you wish to do this, please put your request in writing (explaining that your interest is in the Number 10 website) to the Cabinet Office Openness Team:

**Openness Team  
Cabinet Office  
Room 4.45  
Admiralty Arch  
The Mall  
London SW1A 2WH**

Email: [Openness.Team@cabinet-office.x.gsi.gov.uk](mailto:Openness.Team@cabinet-office.x.gsi.gov.uk)

### Information we collect from visitors

#### Email comments and questions

If you send an enquiry by email it may not always be possible for the Number 10 Web Team to provide the information requested directly. In such circumstances we may pass your enquiry to another government department so that they can fulfil your information request.

#### Email Number 10

It is possible to email the Prime Minister’s Office using the link below. If, however, your issue is personal or you wish to be assured of a direct response to your query it may be better to write to Number 10 using the postal address. Responses to emails cannot, unfortunately, be guaranteed due to the volume received.

#### Newsletters

If you sign up to receive Newsletters from the PM we will use the information you give us to provide the service(s) you have requested. We may occasionally contact subscribers to help us evaluate and improve the service that we offer.

If you sign up for a subscription email service, we will hold the information you have provided for as long as you require access to the service requested. If you inform us that you wish to cancel a subscription we will remove you from our mailing list and your details will be deleted from our records.

#### Cookies

When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. Where services are delivered on the internet, this sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, for example, computer or mobile phone. These include small files known as cookies. They cannot be used to identify you personally.

These pieces of information are used to improve services for you through, for example:

  * enabling a service to recognise your device so you don’t have to give the same information several times during one task
  * recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don’t need to do it for every web page requested
  * measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there’s enough capacity to ensure they are fast

You can manage these small files yourself and learn more about them through [Internet browser cookies – what they are and how to manage them](http://www.direct.gov.uk/en/SiteInformation/DG_197506?CID=Central&PLA=url_mon&CRE=managing_cookies "Managing cookies")

#### Our use of cookies

When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. Where services are delivered on the internet, this sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, for example, your computer or mobile phone. These include small files known as cookies. They cannot be used to identify you personally.

These pieces of information are used to improve services for you through, for example:

  * recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don’t need to do it for every web page requested
  * measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there’s enough capacity to ensure they are fast
  * analysing anonymised data to help us understand how people interact with govt services so we can make them better

You can manage these small files and learn more about them from the article, [Internet Browser cookies- what they are and how to manage them](http://www.direct.gov.uk/en/SiteInformation/DG_197506?CID=Central&PLA=url_mon&CRE=managing_cookies "Cookies article")

Learn how to [remove cookies set on your device](http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=1%27Our%20use%20of%20cookies%27 "removing cookies")

There are two types of cookie you may encounter when using www.number10.gov.uk :

**First party cookies** : these are our own cookies, controlled by us and used to provide information about usage of our site.

**Third party cookies** : these are cookies found in other companies’ internet tools which we are using to enhance our site, for example Facebook or Twitter have their own cookies, which are controlled by them.

### First party cookies

**Number 10 Gov**

*.number10.gov.uk (Number 10 websites) uses cookies in several places – we’ve listed each of them below with more details about why we use them and how long they will last.

We will endeavour to let you know before we store a cookie on your computer.

**Cookies set by Number 10 website**

**Name** | **Purpose** | **Typical content** | **Expires**  
---|---|---|---  
ci_session | Authentication session to prevent having to login multiple times in one browser session. | Hashed data of username and authentication status [only at transparency.number10.gov.uk] | Expires on exit  
  
### Third party cookies

We use a number of suppliers who may also set cookies on their websites’ on its behalf. The Number 10 does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the third party websites for more information about these.

Provider | **Name** | **Purpose** | **More info**  
---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics | _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. | [Google Privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en_uk/policies/privacy/)  
Share This | __uset  
__stid | Tracks what is being shared and by whom | [Share This privacy](http://sharethis.com/privacy)  
Storify | _chartbeat2  
storify-session  
mp_super_properties |  |   
Cover It Live | sessionid_xxxxxxx | Session cookie for the Cover It Live events page | [Cover It Live Privacy policy](http://www.coveritlive.com/index.php?option=com_content&task=view&id=47)  
YouTube | VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE |  | [Google Policies and Principles](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/policies/privacy/key-terms/#toc-terms-cookie)  
Facebook | datr  
lu | Facebook Social Plugin – embedding Facebook content | [Facebook privacy policy](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/)  
Silverpop | SESSION  
SP_PAGE_VISIT.236775  
VIEW | Identify subscription to the newsletter | [Silverpop privacy policy](http://www.silverpop.com/marketing-company/trust/privacy/privacy.html)  
ImageFlickr | uvc  
uuid  
clid  
ipinfo  
acs |  | [ImageFlickr privacy policy](http://imapflickr.com/privacy.aspx)  
Google Map | NNID  
PREF |  | [Google Privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en_uk/policies/privacy/)  
  
#### How to control and delete cookies

We will not use cookies to collect personally identifiable information about you.

However, if you wish to restrict or block the cookies which are set by our website, or indeed any other website, you can do this through your browser settings. The ‘Help’ function within your browser should tell you how.

Alternatively, you may wish to visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) which contains comprehensive information on how to do this on a wide variety of browsers. You will also find details on how to delete cookies from your machine as well as more general information about cookies.

Please be aware that restricting cookies may impact on the functionality of our website.

If you wish to view your cookie code, just click on a cookie to open it. You’ll see a short string of text and numbers. The numbers are your identification card, which can only be seen by the server that gave you the cookie.  
For information on how to do this on the browser of your mobile phone you will need to refer to your handset manual.

To opt-out of third-parties collecting any data regarding your interaction on our website, please refer to their websites for further information.

#### Log files

Log files allow us to record visitors’ use of the site. The Number 10 Web Team puts together log file information from all our visitors, which we use to make improvements to the layout of the site and to the information in it, based on the way that visitors move around it. Log files do not contain any personal information about you.

If you receive the HTML-formatted version of a newsletter, your opening of the newsletter email is notified to us and saved. Your clicks on links in the newsletter are also saved. These and the open statistics are used in aggregate form to give us an indication of the popularity of the content and to help us make decisions about future content and formatting.

#### Linking to another site from the Number 10 website

Our website contains links to other sites, mainly those of other government departments, but also to those of other third parties. The Prime Minister’s Office is not responsible for the privacy practices within any of these other sites. You should be aware of this when you leave the Number 10 website and we encourage you to read the privacy statements on other websites you visit.

#### Changes to this privacy policy

If this privacy policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page ensures that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties.
